<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects/Posts on Sunil S. Singh</title>
    <link>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects/Posts on Sunil S. Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT: Landmarks Classification &amp; Tagging</title>
      <link>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/landmark-classification-tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/landmark-classification-tagging/</guid>
      <description>Here we tackle a multi-label-classification problem. Photo sharing and photo storage services like to have location metadata for each photo that is uploaded. If no location metadata for an image is available, one way to infer the location is to detect and classify a discernible landmark in the image manually which is a very big ask if number of images are large. In this project we&amp;rsquo;ll try to address this problem by building Neural Network (NN) based models to automatically predict the location of the image based on any landmarks depicted in the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT: BikeShare Riders Prediction</title>
      <link>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/bike-share-users-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/bike-share-users-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Here we tackle a Regression problem. In this project we will build a simple multi-layer-perceptron (MLP) or a Deep Neural Network (DNN) model to predict the number of riders BikeShare would get on a given day. MLP/NN will be build from scratch just using numpy. We will not use any sophisticated deep-learning libraries such as PyTorch or Tensorflow for building and training the network. The main aim here is to build each component of the network from ground-up in order to get the deeper understanding of inner workings of a typical deep neural network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT: Face Mask Detection</title>
      <link>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/face-mask-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/face-mask-detection/</guid>
      <description>Project aims to design, implement and compare multitude machine learning models utilizing modern ML and DL techniques to discriminate between the images of human faces wearing or not wearing facemasks. Problem at hand here is a binary-classification task.
Face masks have proven to be very effective against COVID-19 spread. Even though facemasks are proving to be very effective prevention measure there are obvious resistance from society in general. However, given the seriousness of COVID-19 spread, in many countries, authorities have started monitor and enforce the usage of facemasks in public places.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PROJECT: Credit Card Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/credit-card-fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sssingh.github.io/DSPortfolio/post/credit-card-fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>In this project we tackle a classic binary-classification problem. Our ultimate goal is to build and train machine-learning models to detect fraudulent credit card transaction.
Credit card fraud is a form of identity fraud/theft. It happens when unauthorized transaction is made using a credit card without explicit permission from the card holder. There are various ways card fraud can be conducted&amp;hellip;
 Fraudster can get discarded receipts or credit card statements that include your account number, and use that information to rack up fraudulent charges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
